Guide to the Robert Ward Papers, 1910-2012 and undated RL.01344
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Operas, 1956-2012 and undated; 3
  - Abelard and Heloise, 1977-1984, 1996 and undated; 1
    - Acts I & II original master, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0014)
    - Act III original master, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0015)
    - "Behind the Footlights," parts 1 and 2, WFAE, Charlotte, North Carolina, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0076)
    - New York Opera Repertory Theatre, dress rehearsal, 29 May 1984 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0156)
    - New York Opera Repertory Theatre, dress rehearsal, 29 May 1984 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0177)
      Marked "no good"
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0009)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0010)
    - Act II, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0014)
    - Opera Carolina, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0023)
    - Opera Carolina, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0024)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0001)
    - Act I, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0002)
    - Act II, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0003)
    - Act III, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0004)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0005)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0006)
    - Act I, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0038)
    - Act II, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0039)
    - Act III, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0040)
    - Acts I-III conductor's scores, undated; 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Acts I-III conductor's scores, undated; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Libretto sketches and drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Music sketches, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Piano-vocal scores, 1988 and undated; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Piano-vocal score original masters, undated (Box 40)
    - Aria: "Condemn not, oh woeful man", undated (Box 40)
      Piano-vocal sheet music
    - Piano-vocal score, manuscript copy, undated (Box 40)
      Includes edited libretto
    - Published librettos, revised and unrevised versions, 1982 (Box 40)
    - Synopsis, undated (Box 40)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 45)
    - Glass mug with opera title, 1982 (Box 83)
    - Framed cross-stich of opera title, 1982 (Box 83)
      "Abelard Heloise NC 82"
  - Claudia Legare, 1973-1996 and undated; 2
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1973-2005 (Box 7)
      Notable production by Minnesota Opera
    - Academic publication on Claudia Legare, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Photographs of productions, undated (Box 7)
    - Claudia Legare Discussion Panel, 23 March 1978 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0007)
    - Acts I & II, Minnesota Opera, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0056)
    - Lecture excerpts, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0069)
    - Act II, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0159)
    - Acts III & IV, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0161)
    - Acts I & II, Minnesota Opera, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0172)
    - Acts I & II, Chamber version, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0173)
    - Acts I & II, Minnesota Opera, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0221)
    - Acts I & II, incomplete, Minnesota Opera, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0222)
    - Acts III & IV, Chamber version, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0223)
    - Acts III & IV, Minnesota Opera, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0224)
    - Dicapo Opera Theatre, Disc 1, 16 January 2005 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0051)
    - Dicapo Opera Theatre, Disc 2, 16 January 2005 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0052)
    - Acts I-III, Minnesota Opera, full orchestra version, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0081)
    - Eastman Opera Theatre, 3 November 2005 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0089)
      3 discs
    - Dicapo Opera Theatre, New York, 15 January 2005 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0094)
    - Dicapo Opera Theatre, New York, 15 January 2005 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0095)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0003)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0004)
    - Eastman School of Music, 6 November 2005 (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0012)
    - Act I, 14 April 1978 (Box 31)
    - Act II, 14 April 1978 (Box 31)
    - Act III, 14 April 1978 (Box 31)
    - Act IV, 14 April 1978 (Box 31)
    - Act I, 1 August 1981 (Box 31)
    - Act II, 1 August 1981 (Box 31)
    - Act III, 1 August 1981 (Box 31)
    - Act IV, 1 August 1981 (Box 31)
    - Reel 1, undated (Box 32)
    - Reel 2, 24 July 1981 (Box 32)
    - Reel 1, 24 July 1981 (Box 32)
    - Reel 2, undated (Box 32)
    - Reel 1, 28 July 1981 (Box 32)
    - Reel 2, 28 July 1981 (Box 32)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 40)
    - Music sketches, undated; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Libretto sketches and drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Orchestral score manuscript, reduced orchestration, incomplete, undated; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Acts I-III orchestral scores, reduced orchestration, 1996 and undated; 8 folders (Box 41)
    - Acts I-III orchestral scores, undated; 4 folders (Box 41)
    - Act I, chamber orchestra version, undated; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Act I printing masters, undated; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Acts II-III printing masters, undated; 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Revised piano-vocal score masters, 1992; 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Unrevised piano-vocal score, 1992 (Box 42)
    - Piano-vocal scores, 1977-1982 and undated; 6 folders (Box 42)
      Includes production notes and Robert Ward's copy with markings
    - Piano-vocal score masters, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Orchestral parts masters and inserts, 1977 and undated; 6 folders (Box 42)
    - Published librettos, 1978-1996 (Box 42)
    - Libretto masters, undated (Box 42)
    - Assorted soprano arias, piano-vocal sheet music, undated (Box 42)
    - Piano-vocal scores with some markings, 1977; 3 folders; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 43)
    - Piano-vocal score, two-act version blueprint, undated; 9" x 12" (Box 44)
    - Act II partial piano-vocal score blueprint with markings, undated; 8.5" x 14" (Box 44)
    - Piano-vocal score, two-act version with markings, undated; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 44)
    - Piano-vocal score, three-act version, 1977; 9" x 12" (Box 44)
    - Act III vocal score photocopy with markings, undated; 8.5" x 14.5" (Box 44)
    - Piano-vocal score, 1977; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 46)
    - Arias: "Lament for Aunt Renie, "The South Must Industrialize", undated; 11" x 13.5" (Box 46)
    - Orchestral revision photocopy, undated; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 45)
    - Acts I-III orchestral scores, original masters, undated; 4 folders; 11" x 17" (Box 46)
    - Act I conductor's scores with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Act I partial orchestral score with markings, undated; 12" x 19" (Box 47)
    - Acts II-IV conductor's scores with markings, undated; 3 folders (Box 48)
    - Acts I-II piano-vocal score manuscript copies with revisions, undated; 9.5" x 13" (Box 49)
    - Acts I-IV conductor's scores with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Notes by Robert Ward, undated (Box 53)
    - Acts I-III orchestral scores with markings, 1996 and undated; 6 folders (Box 53)
  - The Crucible, 1961-2012 and undated; 3
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1961-2008; 8 folders (Box 7)
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1961-2008; 9 folders (Box 8)
    - Newspaper clippings from first and second performances, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
    - Performances in Korea and Japan, 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box 8)
      Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews
    - Performances in Chicago and at Duke University, 1985-1987 (Box 8)
    - Performance at Opera Carolina, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Academic publications on The Crucible, 1971-2005 and undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
      Includes published articles, doctoral dissertations, and a master's thesis
    - Inspiration and writing process, undated (Box 8)
      Includes photocopies of 17th century letters
    - Production photographs, 1985-1999 and undated; 8 folders (Box 9)
      Includes productions by the Washington Opera, Japanese production in Osaka, and South Korean production in Seoul
    - Posters, 2012 and undated (Box 12)
    - Posterboards, poster, 1983-1985 (Box 13)
      Korean and Japanese productions
    - Acts I and II, Chicago Opera Theatre, conducted by Mark Flint, 1 June 1985 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0009)
    - Acts III and IV, chicago Opera Theater, conducted by Mark Flint, 1 June 1985 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0010)
    - Kansai Nikikai Opera Company, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0011)
    - Highlights from Inspiration Point, 1992 Opera Festival (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0012)
      Aired on "Arkansas Performance" KLRE in Little Rock, 4 July 1993
    - Act III tape music from 56, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0013)
    - Act III Tape music from 56, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0019)
      "As taped piano chord dies orchestra and singers begin at 56"
    - Music for Our Times, WCPE, 4 October 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0050)
    - American Festival for the Arts, 11 June 1996 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0074)
    - Unknown performers, 6 April 2001 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0139)
    - Aria excerpts, The Washington Opera 1998-1999 season preview (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0003)
    - New York City Opera, conducted by Emerson Buckley, 1989 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0015)
      2 discs
    - Pennsylvania Opera Theater, 5 November 1988 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0092)
    - Microfilm of orchestral score, reduced version, undated (Box 26)
    - Boston Opera Collaborative, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0001)
    - Boston Opera Collaborative, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0002)
    - Hungarian Production, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0011)
    - Encore DVD, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0013)
    - New York City Opera, conducted by Emerson Buckley, 1989 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0098)
    - Osaka performance, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0018)
    - New York performance, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0019)
    - Abbey Opera, England, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0020)
    - Tri-Cities Opera, 9-10 March 1995 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0021)
    - The Pennsylvania Opera Theater, 5 November 1988 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0022)
    - New York City Opera, 1961 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0007)
    - The original scream, Ussachevsky, undated (Box 31)
    - Act III tape sounds, raw material, reel 1, undated (Box 31)
    - Act III tape sounds, raw material, reel 2, undated (Box 31)
    - Side 1, uncut, used for remastering, 13 September 1962 (Box 32)
    - Side 2, used and remastered, 1 October 1962 (Box 32)
    - Side 3, used and remastered, 1 October 1962 (Box 32)
    - Side 4, used and remastered, 1 October 1962 (Box 32)
    - Piano-vocal score, 1962 (Box 33)
    - German piano-vocal scores, 1963; 4 folders (Box 33)
      Includes Robert Ward's copy with markings
    - Korean piano-vocal scores with markings, 1963; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Acts I-IV orchestral score with markings, 1963; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Acts II, III, IV orchestral scores, reduced orchestra, undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Arias: "It's a Good Time is Springtime," "I am John Proctor", undated (Box 33)
    - Aria masters: "John, I Knew You'd Come Back to Me", undated (Box 33)
    - Act II string parts, undated (Box 33)
    - Published libretto by Bernard Stambler, 1961 (Box 33)
    - Libretto sketches and drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Stage directions, undated (Box 33)
    - Enlarged piano-vocal score with markings, undated (Box 34)
    - Set drawings, undated (Box 34)
    - Music sketches, undated; 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Corrected engraved proof of piano-vocal score, undated (Box 35)
    - Acts I-II conductor's score, manucript copy with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Acts III-IV conductor's scores, manuscript copy with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Act I conductor's score, reduced orchestra, undated (Box 35)
    - Acts II-III conductor's scores, reduced orchestra, undated; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Act IV conductor's score, reduced orchestra, undated (Box 37)
    - Acts I-IV conductor's scores, no markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - T-shirt, undated (Box 83)
      Signed by the Kansas State Uuniversity Opera Theatre cast and crew
    - Libretto and vocal scores used by Emerson Buckley, undated; 3 folders (Box 89)
  - A Friend of Napolean, 2002-2005 and undated; 4
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 2002-2005 (Box 9)
    - Act II, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0053)
    - Music sketches, undated; 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Music sketches and libretto drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Richard's Connell's story, masters and original, undated (Box 53)
    - Published libretto, 2005 (Box 53)
    - First draft of libretto, Mary Ward, undated (Box 53)
    - Libretto proofs, drafts, and rewrites, 2002-2005 and undated; 4 folders (Box 53)
    - Piano-vocal score corrected proofs, 2004 and undated; 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Orchestral score corrected proofs, undated; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Proofing notes, undated (Box 53)
    - Piano-vocal score, unedited printing masters, 2005; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Piano-vocal scores, 2005; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Acts I-II orchestral scores with markings, 2005 (Box 54)
  - He Who Gets Slapped (Pantaloon), 1956-1986 and undated; 5
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1956-1986 (Box 9)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts production photograph, undated (Box 12)
    - Robert Ward Rehearsal, Dekalb Symphony Orchestra, 22 May 1989 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0128)
    - Acts I & II, North Carolina School of the Arts Opera Department, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0140)
      Conducted by Norman Johnson
    - Acts I & beginning of Act II, North Carolina School of the Arts Opera Department, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0141)
    - Act III, North Carolina School of the Arts Opera Department, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0142)
    - Part III to completion, North Carolina School of the Arts Opera Department, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0143)
    - Acts I & II, Columbia Opera Workshop, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0144)
    - Acts I & II, Columbia Opera Workshop, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0145)
    - Acts I & II, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0146)
    - Act III, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0147)
    - Act III, original version, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0148)
      "B side includes only Mancini's revised aria from 31 to 37."
    - Conclusion, Dekalb Symphony Orchestra, 20 May 1989 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0149)
    - Ward Opera Demo #1, excerpts, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0046)
    - Act III, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0056)
    - The Listeners, William Parker, baritone, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0072)
    - Act I, Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0023)
      lacquer disc
    - Act II, Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0024)
    - Act III, Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0025)
    - World Premiere, Act I, Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 31)
    - World Premiere, Act II, Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 31)
    - World Premiere, Act III, Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 31)
    - Acts I-III Pantaloon conductor's scores with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Acts II-III orchestral scores with markings, undated; 2 folders; 12.5" x 17" (Box 51)
    - Act I orchestral score with markings, undated; 12.5" x 17" (Box 52)
    - Music sketches, undated; 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Orchestral score, incomplete masters, undated (Box 52)
    - Piano-vocal score with markings, undated; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 52)
    - Libretto drafts, undated (Box 54)
    - Published libretto, 1959 (Box 54)
    - Piano-vocal scores with markings, 1961; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Arias: "Ballad from Pantaloon," "Come Close, My Beloved, Come Close", 1957 and undated; 2 folders (Box 54)
  - The Lady from Colorado, 1964-1990 and undated; 6
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1964-1990 (Box 9)
    - Autographed photograph of Mary Jennings, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Poster, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Excerpts, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0132)
    - Excerpts, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0133)
    - Original completion of Act II, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0153)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0017)
    - Original orchestral score, undated; 2 folders; 12" x 18" (Box 57)
    - Piano-vocal scores with markings, undated; 3 folders; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 58)
    - Arias: "Hail, Hail, Hail the Bride," "Vamos Muchacho", undated; 2 folders; 11" x 17" (Box 59)
      Orchestral score, piano-vocal sheet music and printing mock-up
    - Duet: "I Ride Along", undated; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 59)
    - Duets: "I Ride Along," "I'm Making a Play for You", undated; 2 folders (Box 60)
      Orchestral scores with markings
    - Three excerpts from Act I, piano-vocal score, undated (Box 60)
    - Acts I-II conductor's scores with markings, undated (Box 59)
    - Libretto drafts, undated; 6 folders (Box 60)
      Includes original version, revisions, and some music sketches
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 60)
    - Paste-up masters for strings and flute for concert duet, undated (Box 60)
    - Sampler miniature score, undated (Box 60)
    - Orchestral score sampler, undated (Box 60)
    - Orchestral parts, includes masters, undated; 9 folders (Box 60)
      Missing harp part
    - Orchestral score, original master sheets (also includes Lady Kate, revised full score), undated; 2 folders (Box 61)
      Music from both operas mixed together
    - Piano-vocal score master sheets, original version, undated (Box 62)
    - Libretto and vocal scores used by Emerson Buckley, undated; 3 folders (Box 89)
  - Lady Kate, 1992-1997 and undated; 7
    - Selected arias, 1995 (Box 0, Cd RL01344-CD-0091)
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1993-1997 (Box 9)
    - Production photograph, 1994 (Box 9)
    - Act I, Triangle Opera Theater, Page Auditorium, Duke University, 20 January 1995 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0134)
    - Act II, Triangle Opera Theater, Page Auditorium, Duke University, 20 January 1995 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0135)
    - Ward Opera Demo #1, excerpts, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0046)
    - Act I, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0027)
    - Act II, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0028)
    - Raleigh Dance Theatre, 1 May 2004 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0029)
    - Revised full score (also includes The Lady from Colorado, orchestral score master sheets), undated; 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Aria: "I Hail this Land", undated (Box 62)
      Music sketches, orchestral score
    - Assorted orchestral parts, incomplete, undated (Box 62)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 62)
    - Libretto drafts and notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Revision notes, undated (Box 63)
    - Piano-vocal scores with revisions, 1992; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Acts I-II orchestral score, manuscript copies with revisions, undated; 3 folders (Box 63)
    - Aria: "I Hail This Land", undated (Box 63)
      Piano-vocal scores, master sheets, choral scores, and orchestral scores with revisions
  - Minutes Till Midnight, 1981-2000 and undated; 8
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, magazine articles, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1982 and undated (Box 9)
      Letters include newspaper clippings and magazine articles
    - The Greater Miami Opera: From Shoestring to Showpiece, a book by Robert Herman, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Production slides and set scene sketches, 1981-1983 (Box 9)
    - Posterboard, 1982 (Box 13)
      Miami production
    - Acts I & II, old version, Greater Miami Opera, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0202)
    - Act III, old version, Greater Miami Opera, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0203)
    - Acts I-III, Greater Miami Opera, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0078)
    - Miami Opera New World Festival, 2 June 1982 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0025)
    - Act I, Greater Miami Opera, 8 June 1982 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0024)
    - Act II, Greater Miami Opera, 8 June 1982 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0025)
    - Music sketches, undated; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Libretto drafts, undated; 4 folders (Box 54)
      Includes first and second drafts
    - Libretto sketches with edits, undated; 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Published libretto, 1982 (Box 54)
    - Summary of planned revisions, undated (Box 54)
    - Acts I-III conductor's scores with markings, undated; 3 folders (Box 55)
    - Piano-vocal scores, 1992-2000; 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Aria: "Oh Cosmos, with your Myriad Stars", undated; 2 folders (Box 56)
      Orchestral score, photocopied masters; piano-vocal sheet music
    - Notes by Robert Ward, undated (Box 56)
    - Act I, Conductor's score used by Emerson Buckley, undated (Box 90)
    - Act II, Conductor's score used by Emerson Buckley, undated (Box 90)
    - Act III, Conductor's score used by Emerson Buckley, undated (Box 91)
    - Libretto and vocal scores used by Emerson Buckley, undated (Box 91)
    - Correspondence, notes, programs used by Emerson Buckley, 1979-1982 and undated (Box 91)
  - Roman Fever, 1987-2002 and undated; 9
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1994-2001; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1993-2002 (Box 9)
    - Triangle Opera Theater production, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
      Budget information, correspondence
    - Production photographs, undated (Box 9)
    - Workshop master, 18 April 1993 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0011)
    - Piano rehearsal tape master, 19 April 1993 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0012)
    - Accompaniment only, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0013)
    - Manhattan School of Music Opera Department, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0008)
    - Excerpts, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0060)
    - Triangle Opera Theater, Reynolds Theater, Duke University, 9 June 1993 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0122)
    - Piano accompaniment, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0123)
    - Excerpts, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0124)
    - Excerpts, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0125)
    - Complete accompaniment, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0126)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0050)
    - Manhattan School of Music Opera Theater, 2002 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0071)
    - "To Sun, To Feast, and Converse," selected arias, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0091)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0005)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0006)
    - PBS production, 2002 (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0016)
    - La Voix Humaine, 18 November 1995 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0030)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0031)
    - Triangle Opera Theater, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0032)
    - Triangle Opera Theater, 9 June 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0034)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0033)
    - WUNC, Dub of master, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0035)
    - PBS version, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0036)